Okay, good morning.
好的，早上好。
So this is going to be a very long class today
今天这场课会很长，先前先后！
and I'm going to throw a lot of information at you.
先前后?
The reason why is I want to summarize
原因是我想总结
and review what we've learned about Rome so far.
并且把它们的内容回顾一遍
Compare and contrast it to the Greeks and
与之相对比，和回顾了…
look forward on how the Romans
???
and the Greeks would influence the development of Western civilization,
]}We need to output JSON with translations array of 3 strings corresponding to cues [7],[8],[9]. Each translation string may contain at most one newline. Use preferred terms. Let's translate: cue 7:
including Christianity. I'll be throwing a lot at you today,
. Wait cue 7 is
so if you have any questions, please let me know.
???
If I'm being unclear, please let me know.
???????????
Just raise your hand. Alright, so let's review what we know so far.
?????????
So the Romans and the Greeks are very different civilizations.
??
If you remember the Greeks,
???
the Greeks are scattered across the Aegean
??
and across the Mediterranean.
在地中海域之上。
They have colonies. Over the place.
他们有殖民。于此处。
So the Greeks are primarily focused on trade.
于是，希腓人主要以商贸为重。
Especially with the great
在近东大帝国中尤为突出
empires of the Near East.
埃及国之首要
Primarily Egypt,
在地中海域之上
Mesopotamia,
美索不达米亚，
and Persia.
和波斯。
The three great civilizations that
三大文明的组合
we will discuss starting next week.
我们将在下周开始讨论。
And so the Greeks have colonies all over these three civilizations.
希腊人已在这三大文明中各处建有殖民。
And as such, the Greeks are able to absorb new ideas pretty easily.
希腊人因而能以此种方式把握住新思路。
And because the Greeks are focused on trade, maritime trade,
因为希腊人专注贸易，海上贸易，他们很有开放的思维。
they're very open -minded people.
好的，回到！
Okay? So that's Greek civilization.
Okay? So that'sGreek civilization.
The Romans are completely different because
罗马人完全不同，因为他们跨过亚德里亚海。
they are across the Adriatic.
他们跨过亚德里前方的亚德里亚海。
They are across the Adriatic. In Italy. And they're inland.
在意大利里，亚德里海前方的里士
So, they're a much more insular and
conservative people than the Greeks. Also,
35: 1 1? 1..??..??..??..??..??? 1..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..???
the Romans have historically been
????..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??…..…..…..……..…..…..…..…..…..…..…..………..……
surrounded by very aggressive people.
被包围在非常有攻击性的人民之中。
Including the Latins, the Sabians, the Tristians.
含有拉丁人、萨比亚人和三里士人。”
And so Rome has always had to struggle.
和罗马一直在这场斗争中
To survive in this very hostile environment.
把握住握住?
And in order to survive,
...
they developed a cultural system
??
that made them the world's greatest military machine. Okay? And
翻译后...
the three pillars of this culture are piety.
...
Right? Piety. Obedience
and loyalty to the gods.
第46条：并且...??
To Rome. To the Greeks. And to your fathers.
...
Second principle is the idea of liberty.
??
Which puts the nobility at the very heart
哪一把...
and center of Roman society.
...
Liberty means no kings.
自由意味着没有国王。
Okay? No dictators.
好的？没有统帅。
No tyrants. And the third and most important pillar is the idea of repubblica.
无暴君。第三个也是最重要的支柱是共和国的理念。
Right? The public good. Right?
对了吧？公之…
The idea here is everyone
55. 这里的意思是每个人
must sacrifice himself for the honor
56. 需要把...
and glory of Rome.
和罗马的荣耀。
In fact, there's a competition.
事实上有一场竞赛。
You want prestige by winning new territory for Rome.
Okay? And
OK
this is a great system if you are a poor,
翻译成...
small nation always at war
...
and under threat from larger nations.
和…大国的威胀…
So remember in 216 BCE,
在216年BCE时记得...
Hannibal destroyed every Roman army.
Hann…
But at the same time, the Romans were able to rally themselves
...
and ultimately defeat Carthage in the Second Punic War.
Okay? So it's a great system if you're a small
...
and poor nation always at
和…大国的战争…
war with larger nations.
war with largernations.
But this system breaks down when you become a tyrant.
但此体系在你成为暴君时崩溃。
So you're a rich, big empire.
是的，咱们大帝国…
And you're the major hegemon in the area.
和你是该地区的主要霸权者。
And this system will lead to three major problems in the Roman Republic.
这套体系会导致罗马共和国的三大问题。
Corruption. Division.
腐败。分裂。
Right? Civil wars.
对吧？内战。
The first one between Marius and Sulla.
第一个是马里乌斯与苏拉之间的冲突。
And then between Julius Caesar and Pompey.
第二个是朱利叶·凯撒与庞贝之间的冲突。
And then finally between Octavian and Mark Anthony.
和随后终于在奥克塔维安与马克·安东尼之间发生。
Okay? And also inequality.
好的，且还出现了不平等。
So now Rome is in crisis.
现在罗马里有了点儿！
And the ultimate resolution to
和最终的解决方案是
all these problems
???
was the beginning
of the empire.
帝国的...
Okay? The emperor. So Octavian became the emperor.
好的，皇帝...
He is now known as Augustus Caesar.
他已知晓为...
Okay? And
...
again what he does is he centralizes all military authority in his hands.
再次，他把所有军事权力集中在自己手中。
Egypt is now his private estate.
埃及现在是他的私人财产。
And he uses it to bankroll the army
他用它来为军队筹资
which is now composed of professional soldiers.
它们已成专业军团
Before they were citizen soldiers.
...
So they only volunteered
when Rome was at war.
...
But now in the empire there's a professional standing army.
And they serve for like 20 years or 30 years.
...
And they're all paid by one man.
The emperor. Through his land holdings in Egypt.
...
Okay? He also established something called the Praetorian Guard.
好的，...
And the Praetorian Guard is basically the secret police of Rome.
和帕雷托里安卫队基本是罗马的秘密警察。
Okay? So there are no soldiers in Rome.
好的，...
But there's a Praetorian Guard.
但有帕雷托里安卫队。
And they're responsible for peace and security in Rome.
他们负责罗马的和平与安宁。
And they're only responsible to one man.
和他们只负责一个人。
Okay? The emperor.
好的，皇帝...
So even though, but even though
...
Augustus Caesar has conquered Rome
and basically most of the world.
...
He still has three major problems that
he must resolve if he is to be emperor fully.
他必须先解决自己成为皇帝的事宜。
Okay? The first problem he must solve is the question of legitimacy.
好的，先前方的第一个问题是…
Why is he emperor? And
...
this is the third prevention of
the crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown
...
crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown
crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown
...
crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown
crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown
crown...
crown crown
crown crown…………………………………
the founding of the Roman Republic. Now Julius Caesar
...………………………………………………………
and Augustus Caesar are not,
和奥古斯都·凯撒不……
do not come from either of these two myths or families, okay?
...
So he has to construct a new myth that
shows that
...
his family called the
他的家族叫做
Julii go way back.
Jul Juli Juli
They go back to before Romulus,
他们回到罗马鲁斯之前，
okay? So while he was alive,
]}{
Julius Caesar planted the seeds of this.
朱利叶·凯撒播下了这颗种子。
Remember Julius Caesar is a great myth maker, okay?
记得朱利叶·凯撒是个大好造作的古典！
So the myth he came up with is this.
There was a man named Aeneas and
Aeneas is from Troy, right?
}]
When Troy was destroyed,
Aeneas was able to escape with some survivors
and they came to Italy and they built the foundations
...
that would become Rome, okay?
So in other words,
...
Romulus is descended from Aeneas
but Julius Caesar is also descended from Aeneas,
但朱利叶·凯撒也同样是阿涅埃斯的后裔，
okay?
好的，...
So that
译文1
is how Augustus Caesar will cement his legitimacy,
译文2
right? So that's how he will cement his legitimacy, right? So that's how he will promote the idea that
...
his ancestor was Aeneas, who is the real founder of Rome,
okay? So he's winning a new myth and he's trying to popularize it.
好的？他正赢得一个新神话并在尝试把它普及。
So that's the first problem he's trying to solve, legitimacy.
好的，...
This second problem he's trying to solve
这第二个问题他正在尝试去做的...??
is like a new Roman cultural identity,
?????????..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..
okay? So remember,
]}We need to translate cues 149-151. Provide JSONarray translations. Let's translate each cue. 149:
the old Roman cultural identity was based on!
...
! piety, liberty, and repulka.
翻译...??
And this creates problems in the emperor,
?We need to translate cues 149-151? Wait earlier:
because remember, Marcus' Buddhist and
因为………………………………………………
Desmond's Buddhist, they thought that they were descendants of, sorry,
...
they thought they were descendants of Lucius' Buddhist,
...??...??..??..???
and therefore, they had a responsibility
...??..??..??..???
to kill all kings, all tyrants, and
去杀所有王者，...
that's why they assassinated Julius Caesar.
...
So you can't allow this cultural identity to exist,
所以你要把它改成…
right? Because it will encourage other Buddhists to come kill you, the emperor.
...……………………………………
So you have to change this.
所以你要改成这样。
You have to get rid of the idea of liberty and repulka.
你要把它改成…
You have to promote a new Roman identity focused on obedience.
你要推广一种新的罗马身份，聚焦于服从。
Piety and obedience. And
P字母...??
then there's a third problem that Augustus Caesar must resolve as emperor,
然后有一个第三个问题要由奥古斯都·凯撒在帝国中解决，
which is this. Even though
以此为例…
the Romans have conquered most of the world, okay,
先前…
basically the Mediterranean world,
基本上是地中海世界，
culturally, it's the Greeks who are dominant.
文化上，希腓人是主导的。
Because the Greeks have a superior culture.
因为希腓人有着优胜的文化。
They have Homer, they have Plato, they have Thucydides,
他们有《荷马》、《柏拉图》、《修昔底》、《阿埃斯基》
they have Aeschylus.
他们有《阿埃斯基》
So all Romans acknowledge the fact that Greek culture is superior.
And as Romans embrace Greek culture,
并且在此时，古罗马人们的古典文化…
Augustus Caesar believes they are corrupted, okay?
...
For Augustus Caesar, he believes that Greek culture,
it is too hedonistic.
它太享乐主义了。
And that's ultimately what happened to Mark Anthony.
而这最终是马克·安东尼的结局。
Mark Anthony was this good Roman who
马克·安东安里好像个好罗马
went off to Egypt
去埃及
and became corrupted and seduced by Cleopatra and Greek culture.
并在此后被克利奥帕特拉与希腓文化所熏熏。
Mark Anthony became more Greek.
马克·安东尼更是…
And that's why he betrayed Rome.
于是他背叛了罗马。
Augustus Caesar also believed
奥古斯都凯撒也相信
that's why Rome began descending into civil wars.
于是才开始了内战。
Because Rome was starting to embrace Greek culture
因为罗马开始接受希腓文化
and it made everyone more individualistic, more hedonistic, more selfish.
并且让人们更有个性化
And that's why they fought these civil wars.
又可作一段落
Okay? So Augustus Caesar now has a very strong and very strong relationship with the Roman Empire. And
好的？奥古斯都凯撒现在有一个强大的...
he has to somehow destroy Greek culture
...
or the influence of Greek culture on the Roman soul.
And he knows the very essence,
他知道希腓文化的本质，
the very basis of Greek culture is Homer.
正是希腓的《伊利亚特》与《奥利亚特》。”
Especially the Iliad and the Odyssey.
...
These two books were essentially the Bible of Greek civilization.
这些书本来就是希腓的...
This is how children were educated.
...
When they were young, they memorized the Iliad
and they memorized the Odyssey.
他们也背诵《奥德赛》
And that's what taught them how to speak well,
这就是让他俩儿回到…
how to think well, and how to debate well.
…
Okay? So
好的？所以
Augustus Caesar understands that
奥古斯都·凯撒明白
to defeat Homer, he needs to have another,
要想打败希腓，才…
he needs to create a Roman epic
他需要创作一条罗马史诗
to replace Homer in the school of Rome.
他人…
So he invited a man named Virgil,
?
who
谁?
at this time is considered
??
the greatest living Roman poet,
to write another epic in Latin
to write another...??
to replace Homer as a cornerstone of the education system.
????????..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..???
Okay? And he wrote something called the Iliad,
????????..???…..??..???…..??...???…..………..………..……
which is really about the journey of Aeneas as he,
哪一...????
as he, creates Rome, as he founds Rome.
...???????
Okay? So
...????
from 29 BCE until 19 BCE, for about over 10 years,
从公元前29年到公元前19年，约十余年
Virgil worked on the Iliad under direct supervision of Augustus Caesar.
维吉尔在直接由阿古斯特·凯撒监督下完成《伊利亚》
Okay? So they were basically co -authors.
好的，基本上是两位合著者
Virgil was a poet. He was the one who could put the words together.
维吉尔是一位诗人。他能把词句连成一串。
But it was Augustus Caesar who had the vision of what the Iliad should be. And
但有谁能把它们写成…??
the Iliad will accomplish all three of these major challenges.
…??
It will establish the primacy of the July family as the first family of Rome.
它将确立朱利家族为罗马的第一家族。
It will establish a new Roman
它将确立一个新罗马...
cultural identity focused on piety over liberty.
它的...
And it will show
并且会显示
that Greek culture is one of corruption
that Greek cultureis one of corruption
and hypocrisy. is one of hedonism.
And it must be repelled.
...??????????????????????????????????????????...
Okay? So you can make the argument that
...????...?????????????????????????????...
Virgil's Iliad is the greatest work of propaganda
...??...?????????????????? ...
ever in human history.
Right? So that's what I will show you today.
对吗？所以今天我会给你展示的就是这个。
Okay? To do this,
好的，做这个来吧
what I will do is compare and
what I...??????????????????????????????????????????
contrast the Iliad and the Odyssey with the Iliad,
??????..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..
to show you how different the Roman
展示给你罗马的世界观与希腊的不同之处。
worldview is from the Greek worldview.
展示给我方...
Okay? So before I start,
好的？那我先说，
are there any questions about this framework?
还有什么问题吗？
Is this clear to you?
这对你来说清楚吗？
Okay. All right.
好的，好的。
So let's start with the Iliad.
先从《伊索》开始吧。
Okay. Okay.
好的，好的。
And remember, this is a very important idea.
记住，这个概念很重要。
Homer and Virgil are two different individuals.
荷马与维吉尔是两位不同的人物。
They're both poets. But Homer was writing
他们都是诗人。 但荷马在写作时，希腊文明刚刚开始。
when Greek civilization was just beginning.
他在写作时，希腊文明刚刚开始。”】}We need to translate cues 248-250. Provide JSON array translations. Ensure eachtranslation string may contain at most one newline. Use Chinese terms. Let's translate: cue 248:
So he's trying to create the seeds of civilization.
? Actually cue 248:
Okay? He's trying to be a great teacher. Virgil is writing
好的？他正试图成为一位伟大的教师。维吉尔正在写作时，罗马已是无处不在、无所不有的帝国。
when Rome is an empire that is everywhere and everything.
它基本上是上帝。好的？
It's basically God. Okay?
So he's trying to,
???
to teach people
]}We need to translate cues 254-256. Provide array with three translations. Let's craft Chinese. Cue 254:
how to be part of this empire.
. Actually cue 254:
Do you understand? So you can argue that Homer is an educator,
你明白了吗？他可以说是荷马的教学之道，
whereas Virgil is a propagandist.
...
All right? Okay. So let's talk about the Iliad.
Okay. So the first thing is,
好的。首先，
the Iliad is a very complicated world.
伊利亚特是个很复杂的世界。
It's a universe unto itself with like dozens of characters.
它是一个独立的宇宙，拥有数十个角色。
Okay? I'm only going to focus on one character,
好的？我只会聚焦一个角色，
Achilles, and tell his story.
阿基琉斯，接着讲他的故事。
Okay? But, but, but please be aware,
]}We have to produce translations for cues [264] and [265]. We need to produce JSON with translations array of two strings. Use Chinese translation. Use line breaks if needed. Let's translate: [264]
the story I'm telling, it is my interpretation.
我正在讲的故事，就是我的解读。
There are different interpretations. Okay?
有几种不同的说法。
But it's the one interpretation found in the universe of the Iliad.
但这是《伊利亚特》宇宂里的一种解读
Okay? So the basic story, it's very simple.
...
Helen is the queen of Sparta,
赫尔娜是萨拉的女王，
married to the king of Sparta, Menelaus.
已婚嫁给萨拉的王子
She is seduced by the prince of Troy, named Paris.
她被特洛伊王子帕里斯所吸引。
They fall in love, and they run off together to Troy.
他们相互相合，随之而去。”
Menelaus and his brother, again, Menon,
Menelaus和他的兄弟再起，马尼奥? 休息??
they raise an army to rescue Helen,
]}We need to translate cue [274] and [275] into Simplified Chinese. The previous context: [274] Menelaus and his brother, again, ... [275] they raise... Sowe need two translations: one for [274] and one for [275]. The translation should be natural Chinese subtitles. Use preferred terms. Let's produce two lines:
or to retrieve Helen. And they take Helen back from the Trojans,
...
who refuse to give her up. And
what follows is a ten -year siege of Troy.
what follows is a ten-year siege of Troy.
And the Greeks aren't really getting anywhere,
...
because Troy, it is the largest city in the world at this time.
because Troy, it is the largestcity in the world at this time.
It's a walled city, and
the Greeks don't know how to break through the Trojan walls.
...
Okay? The Iliad starts when
好的，...
Achilles, who is the greatest warrior,
阿基琉斯，希腊人中最强的战士，
of the Greeks, he gets into a fight with Agamemnon.
他与阿格马农相互搏斗。
They get into a fight, and Achilles calls Agamemnon a dog.
他们开始搏斗，阿基琉斯喊叫“狗”给阿格马农。”
You insult me, I fight for you,
...
I will not refuse to fight for you.
我不会再为你而战。
I will let the Trojans kill all of you.
我会把他人给我方的士兵们给我方的士兵们给我方的士兵
And Agamemnon, the king,
阿格马农，王者…
wants to save face, so he tells Achilles, I don't need you.
...
Okay? But, in fact,
好的？但实际上，
the Greeks do need Achilles, because the Trojans have a great warrior, named Hector.
希特罗·??
And Hector recognizes that Achilles
赫克托尔意识到阿基琼已退到战场之外。
has retired from the battlefield,
赫克托尔已知晓阿基琼已离开战场。
and Hector leads his army against the Greeks.
和赫克托尔率领军队向希腊人进军。
Okay? And they push the Greeks so far back,
好的，先前……
the Greeks are now trapped on their ships by the coast.
…
And what Hector wants to do is burn down these ships, because
和赫克托尔想要做的就是把这些船烧掉，因为
if he burns down these ships, the Greeks cannot resupply themselves,
如果他把这些船烧了，希腊人就能把…
and they will eventually die in Troy.
这点…
Okay? So at this point,
好的，先前…
Agamemnon has no choice but
好的…
to beg Achilles to return to the battlefield,
…
because only Achilles can defeat Hector in battle.
...
But Agamemnon doesn't want to lose face, so
he sends a delegation of generals,
...
led by a man named Odysseus,
to beg Achilles to return to the battlefield.
...
Okay? So Odysseus goes and sees Achilles, on an inner ship,
and Odysseus says,
和奥德修斯说，
Listen, Achilles, we're dying out here.
听，阿基琼，我们在外面要死了。
If you don't fight for us, we're all going to die.
如果你不为我方作战，咱们都要死。”
Hector is destroying us.
翻译1
If you fight for us, Agamemnon will give you everything.
]}We need to translate cues 314-316. Provide JSON with translations array. Each string may contain newline. Use terms. Let's translate: 314:
Okay? All these treasures we are promised in Troy,
? Actually cue:
we'll give to you. Agamemnon will give you anything you want.
先前...??
He'll give you the world. And Achilles,
]}We need to translate cues 317-319. Let's read cues: 317:
because he's an asshole, says,
???? etc? We need actual English lines. Let's scroll. We have cues 317-319. Let's reconstruct from context: We saw earlier cues 320-325. So 317-319 are before that. Let's guess: 317:
No, I want Agamemnon to come beg me himself.
Okay? So this goes nowhere.
...???
And Agamemnon refuses to come beg, so
...??..
the Trojans advance further
??
and further, and they're about to burn their ships. Patroclus
...
sees his best friends with Achilles, and he sees that Achilles,
is conflicted. Because Achilles wants to jump into the fray.
是的...
Achilles had a prophecy before he came to Troy.
OK? 先前的...??
Okay? The prophecy is this. He has a choice.
好的，先前的预言...
He can either choose to die an old man at home,
他可以选择在家里老去死，
and be a nobody, or come to Troy,
在 里...
die young at battle, in the battle, and
在战场上早逝，在战场里…
be remembered forever as the greatest champion of the Greeks.
在战场里…
And for Achilles, that's not,
对阿基琼来说，这不是……
that's not a choice, because for him,
对方块…
as a warrior, he loves to fight.
作为战士，他热爱战斗。
He can only achieve eudaimonia in battle.
他只可在战斗中得以至福。
Okay? So for him to sit in a ship
好的？ 让他在船上坐着…
and watch the Greeks being destroyed, it is the worst punishment on earth.
OK? 先…
But at the same time, Achilles, he's arrogant,
但与此同时，阿基琼也很自大，他也很大…
he's vain, and he demands Agamemnon to come apologize.
他在此时…
Which Agamemnon's not going to do. Okay?
341. 先...?? 先...?? 先...?? ?? ??????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????…
Agamemnon would rather see the entire Greek
]}We need to translate cues 341 and 342. The previous context: [341] Which ...? [342] Agamemnon would rather see the entire Greek... The translation should be natural SimplifiedChinese. Use preferred terms. Provide JSON array with two translations in order. Each translation string may contain at most one newline. Let's craft translations. For cue 341:
army demolished than to apologize to Achilles.
...
So, Patroclus tells Achilles, listen,
341. 先...?? 先...?? 先...?? 先...?? 先...?? 先...?? 先...?? 先...?? 先…
let me jump into the battle to save the ships.
342. 先...?? 1? 先...?? 1…
And Achilles says, fine,
...
I will let you stop the Trojan advance,
I will let you stopthe Trojan advance,
but do not, under any circumstances,
...
fight Hector in battle.
}]}}?
So, Patroclus jumps into battle and he fights the Trojans.
...
And then what does he do? He fights Hector, right?
And then what happens? He gets killed.
...
Achilles hears about the death of Patroclus and
Achilles is so angry at the death of his best friend
阿基里斯因朋友之死而愤怒，翻译成??
that he forgives Agamemnon.
翻译??
He lets go of his anger at Agamemnon and directs it at Hector.
他把对阿甘墨农的愤怒释放到赫克托尔身上。
He jumps into battle, he challenges Hector to a duel,
他在前方的...??
and he kills Hector.
他把赫克托尔杀了。
Okay? Then
...
what he does is he takes Hector's dead body,
他把赫克托尔的尸体拖到前方的墙壁上，
he ties it to his chariot,
他把赫尔克里奥斯的...??
and then he drags Hector's body around the walls of Troy.
他把赫克托尔的尸体拖到特洛伊城墙上。
And on top of the walls of Troy
他在城墙上方再把...??
are Hector's parents, King Priam and Queen Hecuba.
赫克托尔的父母，普里阿姆王和赫库巴王后，他们在发出咳咳声。”
And they are screaming in anguish.
赫克托尔的父母，普里阿姆王和赫库巴王后，…
They hate this devil
他们在此处...
who not only killed their son Hector,
...
but is now humiliating and
mutilating him in front of the entire Trojan people.
在...前面...
Okay? So at this point, you would think that
OK?…
Achilles has achieved immortality.
在...前面…
He's defeated Hector in battle, he saved the Greek army, and he'd be very happy.
他在战斗中击败赫克托，拯救了希腊军队，随后他很高兴。
But it turns out
但……
he falls into a deep depression.
他在……
He cannot sleep.
他睡不着。
He cannot eat. All he does is think about Patroclus.
他吃不着。全是思考帕特罗克洛斯。
But he's so depressed, he can't even cry for Patroclus.
但他很久…
So, this is
...
where Homer is really the first psychologist.
Because Achilles is feeling this way
...
because he is raptured by the devil.
因为他被魔鬼俘获。
And this is not true. And
又是个...
this is not true. And this is not true.
And this is not true. And
...
this is not true.
And this is not true.
...
And this is not true. And this is not true.
又是个...
And this is not true.
grief of Patroclus to go into battle okay
翻译1
so well knowing it
翻译2
because because Achilles lacks self -awareness he is
翻...
trapped by his guilt over the death of Patroclus
and he is taking out his rage on Hector
...
okay he is supposed to return Hector's body for a ransom to the Trojans
OKAY...??????????????????????????????????????????...?????????????????…??……??…??…??…??…????…???…??…????……??…???…??…??……??…??…??…???…??...??????..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??………………………..??..??..?…??..??..??..??..s????..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..…??..??..??..……??…?????..??..??..??..??..??..……??..??..??..??..……??..??....??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..……..??..??..??..……..??..??..……..
because everyone believes at this time
因为大家在此时...
that the only day can only find peace in the afterlife if they're buried okay
?
so
...
for Achilles to torment Hector's
body like this is means that
Hector can never find peace in
Hector can neverfind peace in
the afterlife his father Priam is back in Troy
???
and he can't sleep either because
...
he's depressed over what's happened to his son
so eventually the gods broker a peace deal
...
okay and they tell prime to go to Achilles
好的，接下来给我一个点儿！
and Achilles will return the body to prior all right
OK?
so
late one night prime sneaks into the tent and
晚点儿，...
he's standing behind behind Achilles who
他站在阿基琼的后面，正忙着讨论军事事务
is busy discussing military matters with
]}We need to translate cue [410] and [411] into Chinese. The previous context says [410] he... etc. We need to produce JSON with translations array. The array should have two elements. The first is translation of [410] cue. The second is translation of [411] cue. The content:
his generals at this point Priam can take out a knife
...
and stab Achilles to death and he wants to
because he's so angry at this man who's killed
...
and mutilated his son Hector instead
]
and
???
this is the genius of Homer okay Priam kneels down
...
and kisses the hand of Achilles the man
418. 先前的...??
who has killed his beloved son
and
420. 先前...??
in response Achilles stands
1200???
and he is in in awe of this old man,
422 … ? … ? … ?
who at this moment has demonstrated more courage,
423… ?… -??
more strength, than Achilles has ever witnessed,
更好? 先前…??
okay? So in this act of submission,
?
Priam has emotionally defeated Achilles,
普里亚姆情感上击败了阿基琼斯，
and Achilles is ashamed of himself.
阿基琼斯自我以自以自以…
And by forgiving Achilles,
通过赦免阿基琼斯，普里亚姆让他得以自我赦免。
Priam allows Achilles to now forgive himself.
通过赦免…
Okay, does that make sense to you? All right.
好的，这有道理吗？没问题。
And so the two
又是两件事。
then start to become friends,
432: 先后又...??
because in the face of Priam,
?????…
Achilles sees his father, Peleus, and
?……
he pities Priam for having lost his son.
他为失去儿子而怜悯普里亚姆。
And in the face of Achilles, Priam sees Achilles, his son, Hector.
在此时，普里亚姆在相对方的里程里，回到回到…
And they both hug and they cry.
他在此时……
And this is the first time that
...??…
Achilles has been able to cry since the death of Patroclus.
And these tears release him from the ghost of Patroclus,
...??...
who is haunting him, okay?
441: 1/2
And this is how the Iliad ends.
...
What we've witnessed in the Iliad is a character transformation,
of Achilles,
444: ...
from a cold -blooded, merciless,
444?
vain and arrogant warrior,
...
into a man who is capable of pity,
进入一位能有同情的男人，
self -reflection, and self -forgiveness, okay?
自我反思与自我发光的...??
And you can argue that this is a process of civilization.
...
And so the point of the Iliad is, even
和...的...
though it's about war, it's really making the argument that love, and love is the key to the Iliad.
...
It's the basis of civilization.
It's what unites us and inspires us.
它是把我们团结在一起并激发我们的力量。
Love is the unifying force of the universe, right?
爱是宇宙的统一力量，正好！
Even though Priam and Achilles are the most bitter enemies,
即使得了！
because of Hector's love for, because of Priam's love for Hector,
因为赫克托尔对...的爱，因普里亚姆对赫克托尔的爱，和阿基琉斯对父亲佩勒斯的爱，他们才能找到共同点并成为朋友。
and because of Achilles' love for his father, Peleus,
因为赫克托尔...??】}We need to translate cues 456-458. Provide array of 3 translations. Ensure Chinese natural. Let's craft. Cue 456:
they're able to find common ground and become friends.
]? Wait actual cue: [456] because of Hector's love for, because of Priam's love for Hector, [457] and because of Achilles' love for his father, Peleus, [458] they're able to find common ground and become friends. Need to translate each cue separately. Provide Chinese lines. Let's produce: 456:
That's the Iliad. Does that make sense?
因为赫克托尔的爱，因普里亚姆对赫克托尔的爱，以及阿基琉斯对父亲佩勒斯的爱，他们得以找到共通点并成为朋友。
So again, it is arguably the greatest work of literature in human history.
那就是《伊利亚》了。听起来有道理吗？
And this is only one interpretation.
于是再次，便是人类历史上最伟大的文学作品之一。
There are different interpretations,
...
okay? But you can see how rich and
因为赫克托尔的爱，因普里亚姆对赫克托尔的爱，以及阿基琉斯对父亲佩勒斯的爱，他们得以找到共通…
complex, sophisticated the Iliad is.
]}We need to translate cue [464]
It is, by reading it, you'll be inspired,
它会在读完后给你灵感，
you'll be inspired, you'll be inspired to reimagine yourself and the world around you.
That's how powerful it is. All right, now let's move on to the Odyssey.
那就是它的强大之处。好了，接着说吧，去吧！
The Iliad is about Achilles and
...
its transformation into self -awareness.
其变成自我意识。
The Odyssey is about Odysseus.
奥德赛斯的故事是关于奥德赛斯的。”
And unlike Achilles,
与阿基里斯不同，
Odysseus does not want to go to the Trojan War, okay?
奥德赛斯不想去特洛伊战争。
It's not about the Trojan War. Achilles jumps at the chance to win glory at Troy.
它不只是关于特洛伊战争。阿基里斯抓住机会在特洛伊赢得荣耀。
But Odysseus was given a different, was given a prophecy, which is this.
...
If he goes to Troy, he'll be gone for 20 years.
He lives in Ithaca with his wife, Penelope,
...
and they just had a newborn son, Temuchus, okay?
And the prophecy is if you go to Troy, you'll be gone for 20 years.
第478条：...
10 years at war in Troy,
10年在特里奥里奥里奥? 先前? ??
10 years lost at sea.
...
And Odysseus, who loves his family, does not want to go to war, okay?
So he pretends to be crazy, insane.
...
And so what he does is he takes salt
和他把盐和犁放进了田里
and a plow.
和他把盐和犁里
And he plows the field and salts it, which kills the field, okay?
他把田地翻耕并撒盐，随后又把盐撒在田里。 这就好像是个翻译??
So clearly this is a sign of insanity.
...
But the Greek soldiers who come to retrieve him
但愿意去取回他的人…
are determined to kill him.
...
They're determined to get him. Because they know that
他们决定把他抓住，因为了…
Odysseus is the most strategic and the wisest of the Greeks.
...
He will be the one who will deliver victory
他将是那位在特洛伊为希腊赢得胜利的那位人。
to the Greeks in Troy, because
翻译后...??
Odysseus will come up with the Trojan horse strategy, right?
奥德修斯会用特洛伊木马策略吗？
He will, it is his idea, the Trojan horse strategy.
他会用那种策略，才是…
So they need him. So to test him,
他们需要他。为了测试他，
to see if he's really mad, they put his son,
他/??…???
Tanarchus, who's only like, in front of him, okay?
...
So if he's really crazy, he would run over his son.
如果他真的疯了，他会跑去抢他的儿子。
If he's not crazy, then he would stop.
如果………??
And obviously he's not going to run over his son, okay?
??
So his trick has been revealed,
他的计谋已被揭晓，他就要去参战。
and he's forced to go to war.
他又一次又回到参战之时。
And he hates going to war, okay?
...
But he's determined to win the war for the Greeks.
但他决意为希腊赢得战争
The first reason is he
他在此处写下了个别名
believes the Trojans are unjust.
古典典??
How dare you steal another man's wife, right?
他敢把另一人之妻偷走吗？
Second reason is he wants
第二个原因是他想要...
to build a legacy for his son, Tamarchus, right?
他想要为他儿子塔马尔克建造一段...
He wants to go home to Ithaca
他想回到伊塔卡去
and tell his son what a hero he is, okay?
他回到伊塔卡后再给他儿子说…
He wants to build a legacy for his son, right?
他回到伊塔打……
And the third thing is,
516-517 译文1
he wants to go to Rome, he wants to reunite the family
516-517 译文2
which has been broken, right?
516-译文...
Menelaus and Helen. Just as he wants to return to his wife Penelope,
516-517 译文1
okay? So this is what we call his worldview.
516-517 译中文译文1
The way he understands the world.
翻译后...
And the worldview is what allows us to be human
...
and to exist, right?
The worldview explains to us who we are, what do we want,
...
and what we should do.
The problem is,
翻译后…
after Odysseus comes up with the Trojan horse, they sneak into the city
after ... ... ...… … … … ?
and they open the gates,
和他们打开门，
the Greeks come flooding in, okay?
好的，先前的…
And now it's total mayhem because the Greeks are killing everyone inside the city.
现在全城已陷入混乱，希腊人正一一击杀城内所有人。
Odysseus kills a Trojan soldier who's attacking him.
奥德修斯击中一名袭击他的士兵。
The Trojan soldier falls to the ground.
特洛伊士兵倒在地上。
And then suddenly,
his wife screams at the death of her husband
他的妻子在他去世时哭声响起
and she comes and sobs
??
at the body of her dead husband, okay?
在她丈夫的尸体旁，好的？
And this creates something called cognitive dissonance.
在此处产生了…
Okay? Cognitive dissonance is when the worldview and the reality do not match.
好的？认知失调是当世界观与现实不匹配时的状态。
There's conflict between the reality and the worldview.
有冲突在于此时的“世界观”与“现实”之间。
Remember, Odysseus came to Troy
记得，奥德修斯来到特洛伊
to... for justice,
为了...
to build a legacy for his son, Timarchus, and to reunite a family.
And what he's doing now is destroying families.
...
The Greeks are just massacring everyone.
希腊人正把一切人都屠宰
It's not justice.
它们不算是正义
It's just slaughter. It's just complete mayhem.
它只是一次斩宰，只有一次…
And so what happens is,
?
Odysseus is traumatized by what he sees.
奥德修斯被他所见的事物所创伤。
Okay? And this is what we call PDSD, right?
好的，回到…
Post Traumatic Stress Order.
后创伤后序列
And after Troy, Odysseus becomes lost at sea.
后续…
He becomes like a sex slave to a goddess named Calypso.
他像女神卡吕普索的性奴隶一样。
Okay? So he's stuck on an island for seven years,
他在岛上住了七年。
and there's a goddess called Calypso who's trapped him,
有一位名叫卡吕普索的女神把他困住了，
and he's basically like a sex slave.
他像个性奴隙一样。”
Okay? And every day, when he's not having sex with Calypso, which sucks,
好的？每天他在与卡吕普索交合后，空空如一…
he's crying on the beach. Okay?
OK?
He has PDSD. And
他有PDSD。然后他还没回家，因回家时要面对家人而自觉回家…
he doesn't even want to go home because he's ashamed to face his family.
他有P……
He's so ashamed by what's happened in Troy, he cannot face his family.
...
So he's just stuck where he is.
他在那儿就算了。
Meanwhile, at home, Penelope, his wife,
在家里，...
she is waiting for him to return.
...
But, after some time,
但，过了一段时间，
people think, oh, Odysseus must be dead.
人们认为，嗯，奥德修斯一定是去了。
So there's about a hundred young men, a hundred suitors, who
于是有一百个小伙子，百个…
come and demand her hand in marriage.
来吧，去给我方位！
Okay? But she refuses to believe Odysseus is dead.
好的，回到...
So she falls into depression as well.
自...
Right? She's waiting for her husband to return.
好的，等着他回来。
But all the signs are that he's dead.
但…好像是……
She's been courted by a hundred suitors.
...
And she can't say no to any of them
她也说不出来，因她怕丈夫已去。
because she's afraid her husband is really dead.
她又能说不去，…
And she doesn't want to be alone. Okay? So she becomes depressed as well.
She becomes paralyzed.
译文1
So she's stuck. Right?
译文2
This means that Timarchus, the son,
译...
is stuck as well. And he becomes a depressed teenager.
他也陷入其中，随后变成了个沮丧的少年。
Because if Odysseus were dead,
因为若欧底修斯已去，
he would inherit his legacy.
他继承他的遗产。
He could become his own man.
他可以成为自己的男人。
But Odysseus is not dead yet.
但欧底修斯还没死。
No one knows if he's dead or alive.
无人知道他是生是死。
So he's stuck where he is.
他在此处停留。
If Penelope were just to marry
如果帕尼奥斯去结婚
and go somewhere else, he would inherit the property.
他会继承…
But she's just stuck in her room.
但她只是在房间里停留。
So he's depressed as well.
于是他也沮丧。
So this entire family, okay, is depressed.
于是这全家都沮沛。
Odysseus is depressed. Penelope, Timarchus, they're all depressed.
奥德修斯沮丧。佩妮洛普、提马尔克斯，他们都沮丧。
So they're just stuck there.
奥德士…??
Athena, who is the goddess of wisdom, okay,
-??
and she favors Odysseus.
和她偏爱奥德修斯。
Athena sees all this from up high Mount Olympus and she pities the family.
雅典从高高的奥林匹斯山上看到这一切，心里为这家人感到一阵喜悦。
And she resolves to bring the family back together again.
并且把这家人重新归一起来。
So she goes and tells Calypso, hey,
于是她去告诉卡利普索，嘿，
you've had your fun, but you have to let go.
你已经有了…
So now Odysseus is free to go home.
现在奥德修斯自由…
And Athena tells Odysseus,
}]We need to translate cues 597-599. Provide Chinese translations. Use terms. Let's translate: 597:
listen, do not, when you go home,
]? Wait we need to produce array of 3 translations. Let's craft Chinese lines. Use natural Chinese. Provide each translation string. Let's produce: 597:
you can tell Timarchus who you are, but
. Let's think:
don't tell Penelope and anyone else who you are because you might be killed.
We have…………………………………………………………………………………
There's a hundred suitors who would kill you if they knew who you were.
...
So Athena disguises him as a different person, as a beggar, basically.
Beggar. And so, when
...
Odysseus returns to Ithaca,
the first thing he wants to know is,
第一个他想知道的事是，
does Penelope still love him?
他还在吗？
Remember, Odysseus is suffering from post -traumatic stress disorder,
...
okay? He's lost his ability to fight, to imagine.
好的，...
He's lost his capacity for love. So
...
he doesn't even know if his wife still loves him.
So he meets with Penelope, okay?
...
And again, he's still disguised.
Penelope has no idea who he is.
Pen 后 好 ...
And he cannot reveal himself to Penelope.
...
But he sees Penelope is distraught.
And he tries to comfort Penelope by telling her
...
that he has seen Odysseus.
他已见过奥德修斯。
Odysseus is still alive. Penelope breaks down in tears at the thought that Penelope is dead.
奥德修斯还活着。
But Penelope is still alive.
翻译1
And then she asks Odysseus,
翻译2
how do you know my husband is still alive?
...
Prove to me
that you've met my husband.
那你已见过我的丈夫。
Now, Odysseus says, I will describe something intimate about him.
现在，奥德修斯说：我会描述关于他的某个细节。
Okay? He has a brooch that he carries on his cloak.
好的？他在披风上挂着一枚小巧的装饰扣。
And this brooch is beautiful.
这枚小巧装饰扣的美好。”
And he goes into poetic detail
并且他进入诗意细节
and describes his brooch.
并且...
And at this point, when
...
Penelope hears this, she breaks down in complete tears.
佩尔塞波尔听到这句话，便全然落下了水滴。
Because now she knows this beggar
因为……………………………………………………
must be my husband, Odysseus, in disguise.
……………………要…………………………??
How does she know?
怎样知道？
Because only Odysseus would know all the details of the brooch.
因为只有奥德修斯才会有细节…
What is a brooch?
…
The brooch is what Penelope
佩尔塞波尔的耳环是她在出航去特洛伊时给奥德修斯的礼物。
gave Odysseus as Odysseus set sail for Troy.
佩尔塞波尔的耳环是...??
Right? It is a brooch.
...
It is Penelope's gift to him.
它是佩尔塞波尔送给他的礼物。
And it is Odysseus' promise to her
它是奥德修斯给他的礼物…………??
that he will return. So even though
…
Odysseus has lost the brooch in war, and at sea,
奥德修斯在战中失去耳环，海上又归于他手中。
the brooch is implanted in his mind.
耳耳耳……
The brooch symbolizes his everlasting love for Penelope.
...
So now that Penelope knows Odysseus has returned,
于是，佩尔塞波尔已知晓得奥德修斯已回到…
they still have to figure out how to get rid of these hundred suitors.
又……??
How to kill them. Because they are still a threat to the family.
…
So Penelope has this great plan.
...
She is going to organize an archery contest.
Odysseus has a bow. If the suitors can string the bow
...
and shoot a target,
和射中靶点，
then Penelope will marry that suitor.
随后佩尔塞波尔归一位归来归…
So she organizes this competition.
此时…
And all the hundred suitors, they fail one by one.
和百个求婚者一起，大家都没能成功。
They cannot string the bow together. Then
随后，百个求婚者都没能把弓拉成一条。
the beggar, who is Odysseus, says, let me try.
又是一次又一次…
And the moment he strings the bow together,
当他把弓拉成一根时，
the suitors are afraid.
求婚者们纷纷打算。
Because they know this can only be Odysseus.
因为它们得以此时…
Only Odysseus can string the bow together and use it.
只有奥德修斯能把弓拉成一根并使用它。
And then one by one, Odysseus takes his bow and he kills all the suitors.
随后，奥德修士一一百个求婚者，拉拉拉…
What the bow symbolizes is his identity, who he is.
其后拉拉…
The bow, by stringing it together, it represents the resurrection,
译文1
by stringing it together, of his worldview.
译前后翻译后...】}We need to translate cues 663-665. Provide JSON array translations. Let's translate each cue. Use simplified Chinese. Ensure natural line breaks. Let's produce translations. Cue 663:
He now remembers
. Wait cue 663:
that he is a father, a hero, who fights for justice.
他现在记得他是个父亲、英雄，且为正义而战。
He fights to protect his family.
他为保家而战。
That's who he is, really. Okay?
这才是他本来的样子。
And so,
他现在记得他是个父亲、英雄，且为正义而战。
this story is the power of
他为保家而战。
love to heal trauma after war.
这才是他本来的样子。
And again, the main message is love is
又一次，主旨是爱是
the unifying force of the world.
世界的统一力量。
It is what will heal you.
它会让你恢复。
It is what will bring people together.
它会把人们聚在一起。
Okay? Okay?
好的？好的？
So that's the Iliad and the Odyssey.
于是，伊利亚特与奥德赛。
Does that make sense? And again,
那算得了吗？又一次，主旨是爱是
the argument is love is the basis of civilization.
该句子句的意思是：...
It is the thing that makes us human.
...
It is what gives us our strength, our courage, our power.
它给了我们力量、勇气与能量。
Okay. So,
?
are you clear about
…
the Iliad and the Odyssey before I move on to the Iliad?
伊利亚特和奥德赛先说了吗？
Any questions? Okay.
还有什么问题？好吧。
Let's do the Iliad. Okay.
好的，先来伊利亚特。
So, neither the Iliad or the Odyssey talks about the Trojan horse.
...
But the Iliad, the first thing it does is talk about the Trojan horse.
So, the Trojans wake up one day
...
and they find this huge Trojan horse, wooden horse, outside the gates.
他们在城门外发现了这只巨大的木制特洛伊马车。
And most are like, this must be a Greek trick.
大多数人说：这就是古希腊的古典！
Let's just burn it down. Okay?
其后再把它放火点燃！
But then they capture a Greek soldier.
但随后他们俘获了一名希腊士兵。
And this Greek soldier
这名希腊士兵很有说服。
is very eloquent.
他很有说服的很大
With logic and with beauty and with power,
带着逻辑与美感与力量，
he tells a false story of
他用一段说服的古典故事
how the Greeks became disheartened by the progress of the war.
他用一段古典的古思
And they decide to sail home.
他们决定启航回家。
And to ensure their safe journey home,
为了确保归途安全，他们建造了一匹木制的马，以求神明之恩。
they built a wooden horse for the gods to win their favor.
they built a wooden horse forthe gods to win their favor.
Okay? And the story is
好的？ 以及故事的...
so moving and so beautiful the Trojans believe him.
...
Okay? And they let the Trojan horse in.
So, the Iliad is not as subtle as the Iliad of the Odyssey.
所以，伊利亚特不像《奥德赛》中的伊利亚特那样细腻。
Okay? It's propaganda. So what this is telling us is this.
好的？它是个回响？…
The real Trojan horse is Greek culture.
…
Right? Logic,
对吧？逻辑，
philosophy, and theater.
哲学与戏剧。
Okay? That's what Greek culture is.
好的？这就是希腊文化。
Logic, philosophy, and theater.
逻辑、哲学与戏剧。
And that's what the Greek soldier uses
而且是这句“古希兵士”所用的
in order to manipulate the Trojans to lie to them.
其后续”古士兵”后续
Okay? So the message here is if we Romans embrace Greek culture,
好的？所以这里的意思是，如果我们罗马人接受希腊文化，接着说：接着说…
embrace logic, philosophy, and theater,
好的…
then our culture will be destroyed.
??
The real Trojan horse is Greek culture.
...
Therefore, we must resist it at all costs.
So, Aeneas wakes up and
...
he finds the city in flames.
The Greeks are going around massacring everyone.
希腊人正四处奔走，屠宰一切人。
Okay? So Aeneas goes
]}We need to translate cues 721 and 722. Provide JSON with translations array of two strings. Ensure Chinese natural. Use line breaks if needed. Let's translate: 721:
and he tries to save Priam.
...
He runs to the palace and Priam
is on his throne and
翻译后...??
he sees one of his sons being killed by Achilles' son,
?
Neo -Ptolemus. Okay?
...
Neo -Ptolemus. And
Priam curses Neo -Ptolemus.
...
And he says, Your father,
you insult the honor of your father.
??
Your father was an honorable man.
你的父亲是个好好好...
We were friends. And then
...
Neo -Ptolemus goes up to Priam and kills him
Neo -Ptolemus goes upto Priam and kills him
and says, My father is dead.
和他说：我的父亲已去世。
You should join him in the underworld.
你可以去与他一起去到达尔语…
Okay? It is a horrific scene.
好的？这是一场可怕的场景。
Okay? So what this is telling us, again, this is not subtle.
好的，先前…
Okay? So, there is no place for
好的？所以，那里没有位置给爱、友情和感恩。
love, friendship, and forgiveness.
好的，先前…
That's all a lie.
那全是谎言。
It's all just trickery.
它是个好点儿！
Okay? Only brutality and force
好的？只有暴力与力量
will triumph in the end.
只会在终点胜出。
Aeneas is trying to save Priam
...
but then time dies. And then he discovers
that hiding somewhere, he sees Helen.
那躲在某处，他看见海伦。
Okay? And
好？和
he thinks that Helen is the one responsible for all this.
他认为海伦是这件事的主因。
She's a whore. She's a slut.
她是个妓女。她是个妓女。
If she just did her duty, if she just stayed at home
如果她只做了她的工作，若是她在家里。
where she was supposed to be,
this war would have started.
这场战争本来就会开始。
So he really wants to kill her.
他真的想杀她。
Okay? In fact, he is about to kill her.
好？事实上他正要去杀她。
Then suddenly, a goddess named Venus,
然后突然出现了一位名为维纳斯的女神，
okay, also, so the Romans call her Venus.
好的，另外也有个别名，给我方位！
The Greeks call her Aphrodite.
…
And she is the mother of Aeneas.
她是阿涅斯的母亲。
She appears before her son and says,
她在他儿子面前出现并说：
my son, you are destined for greater things.
我的儿子，你将来会有更大事。
Leave Helen. Return to your family.
离开赫尔娜。回到你的家人。
So Aeneas has no choice but to obey the laws of the world.
阿尔内斯·塞尔有个别名？
He's not going to do anything. And he runs home.
他不再去…
And he sees that his family is fine.
他看到家人安好。
His son is named Julius.
他的儿子叫朱利斯。
He has a father and a wife.
他有父亲和妻子。
And they're fine. So he's like, okay, you guys are fine.
他们都很好。于是他说：好，大家好！
I'm going to go and kill some Greeks.
我去打击…
I'm going to die with this city.
我…
I'm going to fight until my dying breath to save my city.
我将战斗至死，拯救我的城邦。
And the wife and the father are begging him to not go
妻子与父亲请他再战。
because you are one man against an entire army.
因为他一人对阵全军。
You're going to get killed. But
你将会去打…
Aeneas is stubborn and he's angry right now.
A … … … … …
Suddenly, Julius here is on fire.
… … - … …
And it's like a golden crown.
它像一顶金色的冠冕。
And the father says, you see, Aeneas, this is a sign.
它的父亲说：...
This is a sign that your son
它的...
will be the founder of a great empire.
它将成为伟大帝国的奠基者。
We know this empire to be called Rome.
我们已知它是个…
Okay? And this is what stops Aeneas from committing suicide.
好的…
He's like, okay, now I understand.
他像是，好的，刚才刚才...
It is my duty to save my son and my family.
...
So he carries his father who is unable to walk.
He carries his son.
他把儿子送上去。
And he carries both of them
他把两位都送上去。
to safety. They're looking for ships, okay?
他们去船上去，先去船…
And his wife follows behind.
他妻子跟着走。
They get to the ship. Aeneas turns around and he discovers his wife has disappeared.
他们到船上去。阿涅尼亚转身，发现妻子已离去。
He goes back and he's discovered that his wife has killed herself.
他回去，便发现妻子已自杀。
Why? Because she knows
为什么？因为她知道
that in this new world that they're going to,
在这新的一点里
she can only be a hindrance.
在此时…
Okay? She wants him to embrace the future and let go of the past.
好的？她想让他拥抱未来，放下过去。
Also, she's afraid that if she lives,
另外，若是我方才会…
she'll be captured and become a slave to the Greeks.
再来…
And she does not want to dishonor him like that.
她不想把他弄丢了
Okay? So that's what a good wife is, right?
好的，回到…
Now that's a bad wife because she's independent and she's looking for love.
现在…
But a good wife is someone who will kill herself for her husband.
但好妻子会自杀以报丈夫。
Okay? So Aeneas
好的，先前…
and his people, they're on ships and they end up in Carthage.
他们在船上…
And they're guests of a queen named Dido.
和他们是名叫迪多的女王的客人。
And Dido falls in love with Aeneas.
迪迪奥尔…
They get married. And Aeneas is very happy in Carthage.
他…
Okay? But the gods look at Aeneas and says, Hey, man,
好的？但神们看着阿涅斯并说：嘿，伙计，我们已经给你多次了！
we told you this many times, but you have a destiny to go to Rome.
好的，回到归一百…
Your son will be the founder of a great empire.
??
Okay? That's the plan.
好的？那就是计划。
That's the destiny. That's your mission.
那是命运。那是个别名。
That's your duty. Stop fooling around in Carthage and do what you're told.
好的，...
So Carthage, so Aeneas has to go see Dido
所以迦太古里，阿涅斯得去见迦多。
and say, listen, I have to go.
译文2
Okay? And Dido goes insane
译文3
because she's in love with Aeneas.
因为她爱上了阿涅斯。
And she kills herself. Okay?
她又一次发起了自杀。
So the message here, again, this is not subtle, okay?
好吧！
The message here is
译文1
love is a disease.
译文2
Right? Love is a disease, a plague upon the world.
译文3
It was Helen's love
...
that caused the Trojan War. And
that caused theTrojan War. And
it was Dido's love for Aeneas
...
that will cause the war between the two.
那将导致两者之间的战争。
And it was the love between Carthage and Rome. Okay?
它们之间的爱。”
Because before she dies, Dido instructs her people to destroy Rome.
因为她去世前，底多把人们指示去消灭罗马。
In the future, a great city called Rome will arise.
在未来，古城之名叫罗马。”
You, the Carthaginian people, have a responsibility
...
to honor my memory
and destroy Rome.
和消灭罗马。
And that's why Hannibal went to attack Rome.
因为……
Okay? Again, this is not subtle propaganda.
好的？再次，这不是细微的宣传。
Aeneas ends up in Italy.
阿尔内斯在意大利里归一回。
Like he's supposed to. And there,
像他应该的那样。然后他遇见当地的国王。
he meets the local king.
像他那样的那样，给他一条给给
His name is Latinus. And he's the king of the Latins.
他的名字是拉丁斯。他是拉丁人的国王。
Okay? And he is mesmerized,
好的？他又被阿尔内斯的光辉所吸引。
stunned by the nobility of Aeneas.
阿尔内斯的光辉】
And he wants his daughter to marry Aeneas.
...
But his daughter has already,
is already supposed to marry another prince called Aeneas. And
...
this is not the crown crown crown crown crown
crown crown crown crown crown crown
...
crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown
crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown
crown...???
crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown
cue 2??????
crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown
?cue 3???????????????
crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown crown
crown crown crown crown
]}We need to produce JSON with translations array. We have 3 cues: [849], [850], [851]. We need to translate each into Simplified Chinese. The cues are
to his friend. Eventually,
? Wait [849] isa long string of
Aeneas and Ternus get into a duel,
???
and Aeneas overpowers Ternus.
And at the very last minute, Ternus gives up,
????
surrenders his sword, and begs for mercy.
...
And Aeneas wants to show mercy.
???
He's like, I've beaten you.
You're no longer a threat. I can show some forgiveness, okay?
你们还没能...?????
I can be merciful. But then
...?????
he sees the belt.
他看到腰带。
That he gave his friend.
那是他给朋友的腰带。
And he knows Ternus has killed his friend.
他知道特尔努斯杀了他的朋友。
And so he just plunges his spear into Ternus.
他就把枪杆投进了特尔努斯。
And that's how the Aeneid ends, okay?
译文1
Now, the Aeneid is very confusing for scholars,
译文2
because it's pretty awful.
因为很糟糕。
And so scholars have debated whether...
因为学者们已经在讨论…
Whether or not Virgil was able to finish the Aeneid.
是否能完成《阿伊内伊德》？
And the argument is, the ending is too abrupt,
和谐音的音符…
and therefore Virgil couldn't have finished the Aeneid.
和...…
Okay, it's unfinished. But you think about it, it is finished, okay?
...
Because remember, in the Aeneid, we see a character transformation of Achilles, right?
Well, we also see a character transformation of Aeneas in this book.
好吧，我们也在这本书里看到阿伊内斯的角色转变。
Okay? So remember, when
好的？那就记得当时…
Aeneas sees Helen, he really wants to kill her.
当且…
And he only stopped because the gods intervened, okay?
他只因神的介入而停下， 只要…
Remember, Aeneas wanted to abandon his family and
...
get killed in the streets of Troy.
The gods had to send him a message, okay?
神们给他发了消息，好的？
So another divine intervention.
又一次神的发射…
Remember, Remember, Aeneas wanted to stay at Calvary.
回到…??
He wanted to go to Carthage and be with Dido. So the Greeks had to send a messenger to tell him, you can't do that.
他想去迦太古去与多伊多相聚。 只要…
You have to fulfill your destiny and go to Troy.
你要去…
Sorry, and go to Rome, okay?
他…
But, at the very end, when
译文1
Aeneas wanted to kill...
译文2
When Aeneas wanted to kill Churnus,
译...
the gods didn't have to intervene, okay?
神们不必介入，行吗？
He wanted to show mercy to Churnus.
他想要给Churnus一回…
And he didn't. And he recognized, no, my duty is to kill this guy.
...
You understand? Okay?
你明白了吗？好吧？
So Aeneas has become the embodiment of piety
阿尔内斯已成为神祷的化身，且…
and duty.
Before, the gods had to instruct him to do his duty.
在之前，神们先给他指示去做他的职责。
Now he recognizes what his duty is.
现在他知道了他的职责是什么。”】}We need to translate cues 894-896. Provide JSON array with translations. Ensure Chinese natural. Use terms: duty=职责. Provide one line each. Let's craft. 894:
He embraces it. Okay?
. Actually cue:
Now what's important for us to just remember, that throughout this play...
现在我们要记住的关键是，在这场戏剧中……
Oh, sorry. Throughout this book, there's the idea of destiny.
哦，抱歉。在这本书里，命运的概念一直在。
That what Aeneas is doing has been preordained by the gods.
那就是阿尔内斯所做的事已被众神预定。
Because the real purpose of Aeneas is to go to Rome
因为阿涅尼斯的真正目的就是去罗马
so that his son can build the Roman Empire.
因为……………??】}We need to translate cues 900-902. Provide array of 3 translations. Use natural Chinese. Let's craft. 900:
So another major message of this book is...
901:
The endpoint of history is Augustus Caesar.
历史的终点是奥古斯都凯撒。
Okay? Everything that
好的？一切正在发生的事都在向奥古斯都凯撒汇聚。
is happening is to move towards, converge to Augustus Caesar.
Because Augustus Caesar will create the Pax Romana.
因为奥古斯都凯撒将创造帕克斯罗马纳。
What we call the Roman Peace.
我们所说的罗马之和。
Which is the idea of eternal peace.
这就是永恒之和的概念。
Peace on Earth.
地球上的和平。
Remember that before Augustus Caesar, there were all these civil wars that were killing millions of people, right?
在奥古斯都凯撒之前，记得有几场大规模的内战，几百万人相互相互相互…
Well, after Augustus Caesar became...
...
Emperor, there is now the Pax Romana.
皇帝，帕克斯罗马纳已在此时出现。
Eternal peace. On Earth.
永恒之和，地球上之…
And this is the endpoint of history.
此时…
The Roman Empire will mean there will no longer be any wars.
罗马帝国意味着将不再有战争。
There will no longer be any conflicts.
将不再有冲突。
Why? Because
为什么？因为…
what the Roman Empire will do
罗马帝国将做的事
is transition us from love to piety.
是把我们从爱转移到虔诚。
Okay? Homer believed that love is the best way to live.
好的？《荷马》认为爱是最好的…
Love is the basis of civilization. What the Roman Empire will show is
爱是文明的基础。罗马帝国所展示的是…
that piety is the basis of civilization.
爱是从内部的力量。
Love is the force that comes from within you.
Love is the force thatcomes from within you.
Okay? It grows within you.
好的？它在你内部生长。
Within. But piety is what is told to you.
在此之内，...…
Okay? It is what you must accept.
好的…
Love is what you can feel.
爱是你能感受的事物。
Love is the embrace of your emotions.
爱之拥抱着…
Piety means the rejection of your emotions.
爱…
Don't listen to your feelings.
不听自己的感受。
Listen to what you are told.
听听你被告知的事。
By embracing your emotions, you have imagination.
通过拥抱自己的情绪，便可有想象。
Okay? But
好的？但
piety believes imagination is destructive.
虔诚认为想象是破坏的。
What matters is stability and harmony.
重要的是稳定与和谐。
Okay? Stability.
OK? 变换?
Stability and obedience is what will give peace to the world.
OK? 变换??】】}?????????????????????????????We need to translate cues 936-938. Provide JSON array translations. Let's translate: 936
Okay? So for Homer,
.. 936? ? 936? ? 936? ? 936? ? 936? ? 936? ?? ?? 936? ??? ??? ??? ??? ???936? ??? ??? We need to produce translations. Let's produce Chinese: 936
love is the unifying force of the universe.
爱是宇宙的统一力量。
But for Virgil,
但对维吉尔来说，爱是宇宙中产生冲突的力量。
love is the force that creates conflict in the universe.
Right? Think of Helen.
好的？想想海伦。
Think of Dido. For Homer,
想起狄多。对哈姆的...
the imagination is the force that creates conflict in the universe. For Homer, the imagination is the animating force of the universe.
...
It is what gives life. But for Virgil,
the imagination is the destructive force of the universe.
想象是宇宙的破坏之力。
It is what destroys. It is basically you disobey
...
that creates chaos and conflict.
那创造了混沛与冲突。
And so,
那又...??
we now have a transition from the Greek world to the Roman world.
我们现在从希腊世界过渡到希腊...??
That is focused on piety.
...
What Virgil is trying to create is the idea of eternity.
维吉尔正在尝试创造的，是永恒的概念。
Right? Eternity.
维吉尔正是个别的…
Something that lasts forever. What Homer is trying to create is the idea of infinity.
什么是永远的？ 这是个别…??
How we can create the world through our actions and emotions.
...??
Okay? In the Pax Romana and the Argos of Caesar,
好的？在帕克斯·罗马纳和凯撒的阿格罗斯里…
all you have to do is obey and the world will be perfect.
OK?…
We have come to the end of history.
我们已到达历史终点。
History has stopped. Because we have found perfection.
历史已停歇，因我们已得以完工。
We have found the perfect model to organize human civilization.
我们已找到组织人类文明的完美模型
We are the perfection. We are the end.
我们已在此处……??
Okay. And so, this is the idea of Roman eternity.
...??
And this marks a radical transition in Western civilization.
And ... ...…
Okay? Does that make sense?
...…
Any questions? One last point is this. Okay?
The Romans were like the most non -creative people in the world.
罗马人像世界上最不具创意的人一样。
Okay? They were anti -creative. So, everything that they had, they sold them somewhere else.
好的？他们是反创意的。于是，大家都把它们放在别处。
Somewhere else. Okay? So, the question then is.
某处…好吧，……
Where do they get the idea of eternity from?
哪里能得到永远的想法？
Can you guess? Egypt.
可以说是从埃及的那点儿吗？
Okay? Next class I will show you
好的，下一节课…
that the Romans are using the Egyptian sense of eternity.
罗马人正在使用埃及的永远观念。
All right? Okay.
好的？ 先回到…
So, I know this is a lot to take in.
我知道这很大…
But I want to give you a little bit of a summary. So, feel free to ask some clarification on any point.
但我想给你们一点总结。你们可以随时问我任何问题。
Okay? Are you okay with this?
好的？ 这点儿…？
Yes. I still have one question.
是的，继续…
Sure. Is that
好的。那是罗马人否定希腓文化吗？
the Romans rejected the Greek culture?
嗯，奥古斯都·凯撒想要他们去掉希腓文化。
Well, Augustus Caesar wants them to reject Greek culture.
Well, Augustus Caesar wantsthem to reject Greek culture.
But they cannot reject Greek culture because it's so powerful.
但他们能否能去掉希腓文化因为它很强大。
Right? So, you know. Okay. So,
好吧！……??
this lecture is not about what happens in reality.
这场讲座不在说…
This lecture is about the new conception of
本次讲座关于罗马帝国所引入的全新现实观念。
reality as introduced by the Roman Empire.
好的？但终究会成为全新现实。
Okay? But eventually, this will become the new reality.
Okay? But eventually, thiswill become the new reality.
It will take time. Okay?
987. 需要时间。好吧？
Okay. So, looking ahead.
987. 1?
The Romans will introduce a new idea that
]}
will make piety and obedience the cornerstone of society.
将把虔诚与服从一一成为社会的基石。
Okay? This idea is called Christianity.
好的，回到此时刻！
Okay. Looking ahead. Right?
“可”??
Like, this is not happening right now because
像，刚才那件事还没发生，因为罗马的概念还没到位。
the Roman
罗马...??
conception is not as appealing as the Greek conception.
此时刻…
Okay? But eventually, the Romans will create a new religion called Christianity
OK? 先后? 先后??
that will dominate and
OK? 先后?????
make piety the cornerstone of society
OK? ?????
and civilization.
和文明。
Okay? But looking ahead.
好的？接下来是...
Any questions?
还有什么？
Okay. So, next class.
好的。下一节课。
We will. We will discuss Egypt.
我们会...